Adrian Beria

+584148811738 | My Website | Linkedin | Github | adrberia@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Senior Frontend Engineer specializing in building and modernizing B2B and enterprise-grade platforms. I excel at taking product visions from initial Figma designs to a production grade applications serving hundreds of users. My expertise lies in architecting and scaling solutions using React and TypeScript that drive digital transformation and significant user adoption.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Consultant | Freelance/Contract Work | Remote

2023-Present

- **Finvar**: Provided strategic frontend development to modernize the company's public-facing presence. Delivered a new landing page built with React and Tailwind CSS, implemented end-to-end tests, and established a foundation of reusable components to improve future development speed in their dashboard (Fintech).
- Revelo: Engaged in a project to train an LLM with algorithms and prompt correction using Next js 15, Shadcn and Typescript.
- Agri Tech Startup (Confidential Client): Engineered a full-stack system to streamline farmer to farmer communication. Developed a Kotlin mobile app with phone-number auth and a map-based report feature, which connected to a backend made with Node, Drizzle and Hono. Also developed an admin panel with React, Shadon and Typescript for managing notifications to the app.

Front End Lead Developer | Memorable AI | Boston, USA

2022-2023

- Rapidly promoted to Team Leader within four months, working on the modernization of a legacy enterprise dashboard to a cutting-edge React, Next.js, TypeScript, GraphQL, & Tailwind CSS stack. Guided a team of five developers in cross-functional collaboration with data, product, marketing and design teams, ensuring alignment with business logic and user needs.
- Architected and developed a real-time Al-powered Campaign Performance Dashboard, transforming complex Machine Learning
 model outputs into actionable insights for marketing teams. Used React Query and GraphQL for highly efficient data fetching and
 global state management, significantly improving data-driven decision-making and campaign effectiveness.
- Led the creation of a specialized LLM-integrated Ad Maker tool, building a custom Image Editor from scratch to enable Al-driven ad editing and instant marketing feedback based on metrics like Ad-Recall. This internal tool was shipped to Product Hunt.
- Implemented robust frontend architecture across all tools, ensuring end-to-end type safety with GraphQL Codegen, managing global client state with Zustand, and designing a scalable authentication system with feature flags for fine-grained access control.

Front End Lead Developer | Vascar Solutions | New York, USA

2021-2022

- Promoted to Lead Developer after 2 months. Mentored juniors, created code guidelines and led a team of 6 developers to build an Al-powered Finance Dashboard (https://beta.capnote.com/) that used React, Typescript and Tailwind. Managed all application state via Redux Toolkit and asynchronous data operations to a Golang backend via Axios.
- Delivered a cohesive user experience by unifying complex real-time features, including interactive social feeds, dynamic maps, financial reports, and notifications, all controlled by a global application state, which enhanced user adoption and experience.

Front End Developer | Tecno Makers SAS | Bogota, Colombia

2019-2020

- Developed an engagement platform for Discovery Channel, integrating social media feeds, strengthening audience interaction.
- Implemented reusable React components and interactive pages for Discovery Channel's main website, measurably improving user engagement and navigation. Ensured cross-browser compatibility and responsiveness for optimal UX across devices.

Front End Developer | Innovative Algorithms | Orlando, USA

2018-2019

• Built a comprehensive dashboard to guide users through product purchases, integrating Google Maps API and Stripe. Developed a reusable React Table component with asynchronous operations, search, sorting, pagination, and filtering capabilities, significantly improving data management efficiency. Used React, Typescript, Bootstrap, Node and Redux.

SKILLS

React, Typescript, Redux, Tailwind, Next.js, Git, Vite, Cypress, Docker, CI/CD, GraphQL, REST, Node.js, Jest, Kotlin, Shadon.

EDUCATION